Okay, we'll briefly talk about the input
tools and techniques
of risk management now.
Now, risk management has seven processes.
We're not going to cover every single
ITTO.
I'm just going to very briefly talk about
these ITTOs.
Again, just to reiterate, it's not a huge
major portion of the exam.
Don't try to memorize them, there's too
many.
And then plus, it only relates to
predictive anyway, right?
Half the exam is agile, right?
So really, these don't relate to half the
exam anyway, right?
So that's why you just need to have just
kind of like a high level understanding.
So again, what we've been talking about in
the other processes, the very first
process in planning in the process grid is
the plan, knowledge area management,
in this case, plan risk management and
what artifact are we creating,
the management plans, in this case,
the risk management plan.
And the risk management
plan is going to be
documenting how we're
going to identify risk.
What's our risk management procedure?
It doesn't contain the actual risk itself.
It does documenting procedure,
documenting how.
And there's a separate, obviously,
a separate video on those, right?
Or a separate video on the risk management
plan.
And then the input and tools and
techniques, right?
The input, remember, is our starting
point.
What artifacts do we need to consider?
The project charter may have some
high-level risks.
It may do, it may not do.
But other components of the project
management plan, are also going to
potentially highlight a risk on a project,
and you can use that to determine how
we're going to categorize
our risks and basically
all the procedures
regarding risk management.
Again, we'll cover the risk management
plan in more detail in a separate video.
Now, you also want to identify risk,
of course.
Identification of risk is done throughout
the project.
You can see this is a very, very big,
busy slide here, right?
Lots and lots of input tools and
techniques and outputs.
Again, don't try to memorize them.
Just have a decent understanding.
We've identified a risk.
Where do we document the risk once we've
identified it?
We document it in the risk register.
And therefore, that's the artifact that
we're creating here.
That's the output.
We're also going to be generating a report
regarding the risk.
So risk report is one of the outputs.
You can see there's quite a few tools and
techniques here that we're going to be
utilising, that we're going to be using to
identify risk.
And again, we're going to be talking about
each of these in a separate video.
Now, why is there so many inputs here?
There's a lot of inputs.
Again, don't try to memorize them,
but think about this.
How do you identify risk on a project?
You identify risks when you're performing
all of the processes on your project.
As you're developing the schedule,
you could be identifying a risk.
As you're developing the budget,
you're identifying risk.
As they're figuring out what resources you
need, you're identifying risk.
As you're performing literally
anything on your project,
you are potentially highlighting
a risk on your project.
You could be identifying
some kind of risk when
you're performing any
task on your project.
And that's why there's a big list of
inputs here.
Remember, an input is your starting point.
These are documents that you need to
review, or artifacts that you need to
review, that you can, artifacts that it
could utilize your starting point.
So basically, any artifact from,
you know, any process along the project
could potentially highlight a risk on your
project.
Now you've identified a risk.
Now we need to analyze a risk.
So you've got a qualitative
risk analysis, right,
where you are analyzing
and prioritizing your risk.
but using arbitrary values, high, medium,
low, scale of 1 to 10,
and that kind of thing.
And then you're coming up with a risk
score, right?
So you're trying to determine the
probability and the impact of the risk.
You're doing a probability and impact
assessment to determine is this a high
priority risk, low priority, so again, you
are going to be prioritizing your risk.
There's other parameters, other factors
that could impact your risk as well.
So that's what this assessment of other
risk parameters refers first to.
Again, these tools and techniques, we're
going to be covering in separate videos.
Now, as we've analyzed our risk,
what else are we going to be updating?
We're going to be updating, again,
our risk register.
We're going to be
updating the risk register
with the probability,
with the impact, right?
Any categories of risk that we've
identified, right?
Any new categories that
we've identified, we're going to
update again, the risk
register, what's our risk score?
So, again, this is all going to be covered
in a separate video.
Now, what's our starting point?
Well, the risk management plan is
documenting those procedures.
Right.
So that's an input.
That's something we're going to be
analyzing, considering.
Notice a risk register is listed as an
input and an output.
So basically, we're going to consider our
risk register to do some analysis.
And then as we've done the analysis, we're
going to be updating the risk register.
That was qualitative.
Don't confuse it with this process called
quantitative.
Quantitative risk analysis.
is also prioritizing your risk,
but this time now based on some kind of
either monetary value, but some kind of
numeric value.
So it could be in terms
of a timeline, it could be
in terms of money, it could
be in terms of resources.
Generally, though, when they're asking you
to do a calculation on the exam,
usually it's going to be in the form of a
monetary value.
And so we're going to be calculating
expected monetary value.
So it's going to be probability times
impact and then that equals EMV again
covered in a separate video now again
there's going to be project documents that
you're going to be updating you're going
to be updating the risk report updating
the risk register right these you're going
to be utilizing some of these tools and
techniques again these are covered in in a
separate video as well and then once we've
identified our risks and we've analyzed
our risks now what we need to respond to
our risk and so these are
some of the ITTOs and input
tools and techniques and
outputs of plan risk responses.
This is determining the approach,
the approach and strategy to figure out
how we're going to respond to the risk and
how we're going to respond to it.
So we have strategies
then for a negative risk
threat, strategies for
a positive risk, right?
A couple of different ways of,
or rather there's different strategies on
how to respond to a negative risk versus a
positive risk.
Again, we will talk about these,
where we've got separate videos on those.
Contingent response strategy, the primary
risk, response strategy again we will talk
about these in a separate video now we
need to plan our risk responses in order
to in the next so how do we actually
implement the risk responses so first you
know we plan now we physically need to
implement and so the implementation then
is part of executing right so we're going
to be influencing our stakeholders now
influencing does not mean forcing,
influencing means encouraging.
And so that's really one of your
interpersonal and team skills here.
And then again, what we're going to be
updating again, we're going to be updating
the risk register as well as the risk
report.
Right now, also remember what's the
difference to a risk and an issue, right?
A risk that materializes generally is an
issue.
Right, well, not generally it is an issue.
So that's why we have issue log that we'll
be updating as well.
That's another artifact.
So that's considered the output.
And then we need to monitor and control
our risks.
We need to track our risks.
Low priority risks have the increased in
priority, right, high priority risk have a
decrease in priority, how much money do we
have in contingency reserve?
Do you have enough money in contingency
reserves, right, to pay for the risks in
case they materialized, and so and so
forth.
So we're going to be basically tracking
our risk.
We're also looking at like low probability
risk, right, there might be low
probability or low
impact right now, but then
there might be increasing
in probability, right?
It might be increasing impact as we go
further and further along the project.
So we have to keep a track on all of these
risks.
And that's really what these are,
what the monitor risk refers to.
And just like any monitoring controlling
process, right, on the process grid,
one of the outputs is the work performance
information, and the information is
basically the comparison of the data,
right, which is executing and the plan.
Remember, monitoring controlling is
comparing actual results with your plan.
Actual results is work performance data.
Compare it with the plan to get our work
performance information.
And then reserve analysis here refers to
risk reserves again.
Do we have enough money
in contingency reserves
to pay for the risks in case they occur?
So these are just some of the ITTO.
of risk management.